ANTONIO OCELLO

(L) +39 348 037 3798 +33 6 16 22 80 95

in Antonio Ocello

antonio.ocello@sorbonne-universite.fr

EMPLOYEMENT

2021 – 2024 PhD in Probability | LPSM - Sorbonne Université (Paris – France)

Funded by École Doctorale de Sciences Mathématiques de Paris Centre 386

Supervised by Idris Kharroubi (Professor, Sorbonne Université)

Topic: My research interests are in Stochastic control and numerical methods, and in particular Quasi-Variational

Inequalities, Viscosity solutions, and its applications to branching processes.

EDUCATION

2019 – 2020 Master 2 – Probability and Finance (ex-DEA El Karoui) | École Polytechnique – Sorbonne Université

(Paris - France)

Courses: Introduction to diffusion processes, Numerical probability for finance, Optimization and stochastic control, Machine learning, neural networks and deep learning, Risk measurements and extreme values theory, Stochastic processes and derivatives, High frequency trading, Introduction to Jump Models, Evolution of Practices and Regulation, Valuation and Risk Management in Energy Markets, Stochastic Algorithms

Mention: Bien

2018 – 2019 Master 1 – Mathematics and Applications | Sorbonne Université (Paris – France)

Average: 18.47/20

2015 – 2018 Bachelor's degree in Mathematics | Università degli Studi di Padova (Padova – Italy)

Mark: 110/110 cum laude

2010 - 2015 High School (Italy)

Mark: 100/100 cum laude

ARTICLE DRAFTS

2022 A Stochastic Target Problem for Branching Diffusions, Idris Kharroubi, Antonio Ocello (in progress)

Abstract: We consider an optimal stochastic target problem for branching diffusion processes. This problem consists in finding the minimal condition for which a control allows the underlying branching process to reach a target set at a finite terminal time for each of its branches. This problem is motivated by an example from fintech where we look for the super-replication price of options on blockchain based cryptocurrencies. We first state a dynamic programming principle for the value function of the stochastic target problem. We then show that the value function function can be reduced to a new function with a finite dimensional argument by a so called branching property. Under wide conditions, this last function is shown to be the unique viscosity solution to an HJB variational inequality.

Tsunami hazard linked to submarine landslides on the Alboran Sea, Sara Lafuerza, Alain Rabaute, Maud Thomas, Jacques Sainte-Marie, Apolline El Baz, Marie-Odile Bristeau, Antonio Ocello, Anne Mangeney, Elia d'Acremont (in progress)

PROFESSIONAL ACTIVITIES

2020 **Off-cycle internship** | BNP Paribas Asset Management - Quant Research Group (Paris, France)

6 months

- Development of multi-factor models on the credit market to generate positive alpha. Model selection, data analysis, backtesting.
- Responding quickly to client queries. Cashflow simulations that take into account the risk of default and the risk of reinvestment. Construction of a client-serve infrastructure and of a GUI via dash.

2019 Internship | LPSM - Sorbonne Université (Paris – France)

3 months

Applications of statistical models and extreme values theory to explain the magnitude of marine risks in collaboration with geologists

Supervised by: Maud Thomas (Assistant professor, Sorbonne Université)

2015 – 2017 Barman | "Al Vicolo", Castelfranco Veneto (TV), Italy

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2021 – 2022 - Numerical probability and computational statistics (Master 1, Mathematics, Sorbonne Université, computer labs)

- Statistical modelling (1st year, Master in Mathematics, Sorbonne Université, computer labs)

- Stochastic calculus (1st year, Master in Actuarial science, ISUP, exercise classes)

2021 – 2022 - Numerical probability (1st year, Master in Mathematics, Sorbonne Université, computer labs)

- Stochastic calculus (1st year, Master in Actuarial science, ISUP, exercise classes)

2017 – 2018 - Affine, Euclidean, Hermitian and Projective Geometry (1st year, Bachelor in Mathematics, Università degli Studi di Padova, exercice classes)

SCIENTIFIC ACTIVITIES

2022 – 2024 **PhD students representative** | École Doctorale de Sciences Mathématiques de Paris Centre 386, Paris, France Representative of the doctoral students in all the École doctorale (ED) 386 bodies (Council, etc...), bringing up requests or proposals, as well as their criticisms, about funding, training, scientific animation or ED policy. Member of the comity for the attribution of ED386 doctoral contracts to following year's candidates. Mediator between the doctoral student and the ED to bring to the attention of the ED a complaint or a request related to the non-respect of the thesis charter.

2022 – 2024 PhD students representative | LPSM - Sorbonne Université, Paris, France

Representative of PhD students in the Council of LPSM

2022 – 2024 Co-organizer of the PhD students seminar | LPSM - Sorbonne Université, Paris, France

2016 – 2018 Bachelor and Master students representative | Università degli Studi di Padova, Padova, Italy

Link between students and faculty members, including participation in meetings with professors and researchers; member of Gruppo per l'accreditamento e la valutazione (GAV), group for pedagogical evaluation in the Mathematics Department

INVITED TALKS

April 2022 PhD students seminar of the LPSM, LPSM - Sorbonne Université, Paris, France

April 2022 Mathematical and statistical methods for Actuarial science and Finance (MAF2022), Università degli

Studi di Salerno, Salerno, Italy

ACADEMIC HONOURS

2018 - 2020 Fondation Sciences Mathématiques de Paris | Scholarship PGSM for the Master's degree

2017 - 2018 Università degli Studi di Padova | Scholarship "Mille e una lode"

Scholarship awarded to the top 3% of the University's best students

SKILLS

June 2019

LANGUAGES ITALIAN (native speaker); ENGLISH (level C1); FRENCH (level C1); SPANISH (level C1)

IT Python, R, L_AT_EX, MATLAB, C++, Mathematica

ATTENDED CONFERENCES AND SCHOOL

/	
June 2022	9th International Colloquium on BSDEs and Mean Field Systems, Université Savoie Mont-Blanc, Annecy, France
June 2022	Third Italian Meeting on Probability and Mathematical Statistics, University di Bologna, Bologna, Italy
May 2022	Stochastic Games and Martingale Optimal Transport, Università degli Studi di Milano, Milano, Italy
May 2022	Mathematical and statistical methods for Actuarial science and Finance (MAF2022), Università degli Studi di Salerno, Salerno
	Italy
February 2022	Journées YSP (Young Statisticians and Probabilists), Institut Henri Poincaré, Paris, France
February 2022	Les Probabilités de Demain, Institut Henri Poincaré, Paris, France
October 2021	Workshop on Mean-field reinforcement learning and applications, King's College, London, UK
September 2021	Les Probabilités de Demain, Institut Henri Poincaré, Paris, France
May 2021	Conference of Numerical Probability in honour of Gilles Pagès' 60th birthday, Sorbonne Université, Paris, France
May 2019	Conférence en l'honneur des 3×25 ans de Nicole El Karoui, Sorbonne Université, Paris, France

Workshop on *Phase Transitions and Particle Systems*, Weierstrass Institute, Berlin, Germany